NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files. 6174/018
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Research & Ed. Staff Meeting, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  01/06/06 at 9AM. Staff meeting agenda; reprint of article from December 8, 2005, New York Teacher, "Combating the Achievement Gap"; special report by the Education Trust, "The Funding Gap 2005: Low-Income and Minority Students Shortchanged by Most States"; campaign trifold brochure (apparent retirement gag), "Yagielski for Congress in 06"
- Research & Ed. Svcs. Meeting, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  01/06/06 at 9:00AM in Conf. Room B&C. Staff meeting agenda; reprint of article from December 8, 2005, New York Teacher, "Combating the Achievement Gap"; special report by the Education Trust, "The Funding Gap 2005: Low-Income and Minority Students Shortchanged by Most States"; campaign trifold brochure (apparent retirement gag), "Yagielski for Congress in 06"; brochure, "NYSUT presents Literacy and Math Institutes," February 11, 2006; handwritten notes
- Research & Ed. Svcs., 2005 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  12/05/05 at 12:30PM in Chuck's Office. Managers' meeting agenda; document, EMSC Deputy Commissioner Search
- Research and Educational Services Holiday Parties, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  Holiday party invitation from the Neiras; guest list; replies
- NYSUT Research & Educational Services Staff Meeting, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  6/20/07 Agenda; 2007 Report of the Vice President; clippings of articles by Maria Neira
- Research and Educational Services Managers Retreat, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  08/26/09 at Sargo's, Saratoga Springs. Discussion materials
- Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  12/21/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; memo from Maria Neira to NYSUT Board of Directors re expiration of terms of members of Board of Regents, possible candidates, December 18
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  11/11/09 at 4PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; revised draft report of NYSUT Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates
- Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  11/23/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda
- Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  10/8/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  10/05/09 at 10:30AM in Chuck's Office. Memo from Maria Neira to Chuck Santelli re meeting to review work
- Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  9/21/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; draft report, "Contracting for Teacher Quality: Annual Professional Performance and Contract Language"
- R & E Managers & PSA, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  09/11/09 at 3:15PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Memo re meeting
- Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  9/8/09 at 2:00PM. Agenda; memos
- R & E Managers Retreat, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  08/26/09 at 10AM in Sargo's at Saratoga National, Crystal Room. Agenda; draft discussion item re next steps for NYSUT for Race to the Top; outline for Southern Tier Summer Leadership Conference; response by State Education Department to U.S. Department of Education request for comments re Race to the Top, August 24, 2009
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  06/08/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; NYSERDA (New York State Energy Research and Development Authority)/NYSUT Partnership Proposal; presentation outline re federal and state efforts at education reform
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  05/21/09 at 3PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; recommendations from the Regents Project Management Group; materials for New Local Presidents' Conference
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  05/11/09 at 10AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT New Staff Orientation; NYSUT capital expenditures budget for 2009-10; budget for Office of the First Vice President
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  04/27/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; materials for QuEST conference
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  4/13/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; agenda for Transforming Assessment and Accountability Systems: A Working Forum for State Partners
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  03/23/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memo re request for PSC (Professional Staff Congress/CUNY) funding
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  03/09/09 at 3:00AM in Chuck's Office. Draft program for NYSUT Local Action Project; agenda and list of attendees at 2009 Local Presidents Conference; planning meeting agenda; timetable; flyer
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  2/11/09 in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; questions for roundtable discussion on the economy and state aid; letter to Kerry Kennedy from NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi re Speak Up Speak Out social justice agenda partnership between NYSUT and Robert F. Kennedy Memorial
- Managers Meeting, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  1/13/09 at 3:00PM. Agenda; draft questions for NYSUT 2009 NEA Accountability Grant; materials re teacher certification
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  11/24/08 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; presentation outline re Federal Policy Agenda: State Input on NEA's Blue Book
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  11/11/08 at 10AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memo from State Education Department re guidance on record keeping and reporting the required professional development completed by teachers and teaching assistants; NYSUT Information Bulletin re the professional development requirement for certification
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  10/27/08 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  10/14/08 at 3:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memos re credit recovery (allowing students to graduate by taking online courses to make up for missed class time), importing thousands of foreign teachers to make up for teacher shortage
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  9/29/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; summary of May 29-30, 2008, meeting with BOCES representatives, State Education Department staff, and others; growth model forums survey questions; New York Post article re credit recovery for graduation by online coursework
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  9/9/08 at 9AM. Agenda; NYSUT Position Paper on Recommendations for Improving New York State's Assessment System; flyer and description of education summit re closing the achievement gap in Title I schools
- R & E Managers Retreat, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  9/3/08 at 10AM in Sargo's. Agenda; retreat materials; handwritten notes
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  6/25/08 at 3PM. Agenda; list of committee nominations
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  6/9/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; draft outline of Governor's Dropout Summit; presentation to NYSUT by James Viola, executive director, NYS Education Department, June 5, 2008; memo recommending against proposed legislation requiring school districts to enforce a disciplinary action against students regardless of whether the offending behavior occurred in a different district
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  5/29/08. Agenda; handwritten notes; memo re Peer Assistance and Review contract language
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  5/12/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; agenda for statewide conference by Capital Region BOCES, "Ready, Set, Grow: School Improvement through Value-Added Analysis"; draft agenda for NYSUT Local Action Project Summer Planning Conference
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  4/25/08. Agenda; memos
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  3/18/08 at 3PM. Agenda; materials for Representative Assembly, including list of invitees; list of pre-RA attendees for Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference; report to the Board of Regents, "Charter Schools: overview of the formation process and impact in small cities"; discussion and action items for Regents meeting
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  02/25/08 at 1PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  02/08/08 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; draft report by NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, "2008 Physical Education Compliance Survey and Summary"; text of budget bill in Senate and Assembly
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  01/26/08 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; outline of speech by Maria Neira re teachers and teacher quality
- R & E Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  01/22/08 at 10:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; 2008 needs assessment survey by bargaining unit leaders; 2008 Newburgh Enlarged City School District Contract for Excellence Survey
- Managers Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  1/7/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; State Education Department progress report on implementation of Chapter 57 of the Laws of 2007
- R & E Managers, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  06/18/07 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; downloaded articles, including Local Presidents' Online Reference Guide; draft letter to the editor to be signed by Board of Regents, NYSUT, and NYS Council of School Superintendents re addressing teacher shortage by allowing retired certified teachers to return to work without diminishing their retirement benefits
- R & E Managers, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  03/21/07 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; report by Council of Chief State School Officers, "Recommendations to Reauthorize the Elementary and Secondary Education Act"; Policy Council presentation, "Focus on Accountability"; agenda and list of Policy Council attendees at March 28 meeting; letter from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to Education Commissioner Richard Mills re testing program for grades 3-8, November 13, 2006
- Research & Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  06/27/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; document, "NYSUT Research Department: What We Do, What We Need"; employment (salary) histories for individual NYSUT staff (CWA or PSA)
- Research & Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  05/25/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Draft language of an SES Rewards and Incentive Policy
- L & RCPC Debriefing, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  05/24/06 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference agenda; evaluation form summaries for various conference events
- Research & Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  05/15/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; confidential (for managers only) NYSUT promotional recommendations guidelines; related materials; list of Research and Educational Services staffing
- Research & Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  01/25/06 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for 2006 Pre-RA Local and Retirees Council Presidents Conference, January 27; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting, February 8; NYSUT-NEA Unification Q and A; resolutions
- Maria Neira NYSUT Statewide Committee Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  12/06/08. Agenda for NYSUT Statewide Committee meeting; comments for review by Maria Neira re possible NYSUT position on modifications to regulations allowing make-up course credit (credit recovery) and independent study, December 3; list of Research and Educational Services committees, 2008-2011; newsletter, Connect-ability, on disabilities awareness, prepared by and for students, 2007, with message from Maria Neira; NYSUT position paper on improving access, support, and employability for students with disabilities, August 2008; guidance paper on virtual learning in New York State; Recommendations of NYSUT's Committee on Education Technology; end-of-term reports for the NYSUT Educational Services committees
- Subject Area Committee Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  2/1-3/08 at 7PM in Desmond. Facilitative memos
- End of Term Reports, 2005-2008 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  Reports by NYSUT Educational Services committees
- VOTE COPE, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  10/28/09 at 3:30PM in Executive Conference Room 2. Revised proposed agenda; financial statements; minutes of March 11 and May 5, 2009, meetings; financial report; resolutions authorizing expenditures; memos re VOTE COPE's tax status; memo re new draft regulations prohibiting gifts of more than nominal value, including meals and beverages, to public officials, January 30; conflict of interest and whistleblower policy; tax return documents
- VOTE/COPE Questionnaire 2008 Fiscal Year, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  10/28/09. Disclosure form for Maria Neira
- VOTE COPE, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  05/05/09 at 3:30PM in Executive Conf. Rm. 2. Confidential memo re change in IRS regulations affecting VOTE COPE's tax status; confidential presentation points re tax exempt functions of NYSUT and VOTE/COPE; related memos
- VOTE COPE Committee, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  04/29/09 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Facilitative memo re meeting
- VOTE COPE Meeting, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  10/2/08 at 3PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; financial report; resolutions authorizing expenditures; list of Local Assistance Rebates; minutes of January 22, 2008, meeting; draft minutes of October 2, 2008, meeting
- VOTE COPE, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  9/2/08. Facilitative memo
- VOTE COPE, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  03/11/08 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; minutes of October 2, 2008, meeting, including resolutions authorizing expenditures; VOTE/COPE flow chart for cash flow; financial report; facilitative memos
- Vote Cope, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  1/22/08 at 2PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; minutes of August 14, 2007, meeting, including resolutions authorizing expenditures; list of Local Assistance Rebates